Elnaz Doostdar iamux.ninja

San Mateo, CA 94403 LinkedIn 949.607.6136 elnazd@gmail.com

## Senior UX / UI Designer

Initiate building and defining maintenance process of a unified design library, cut design time by half, and accelerated rebranding process. Recognized by leading user testing efforts and improving conversion rate by validating design decisions on marketing, e-commerce, support, partners, and community sites with users.

Create simple solutions for complex issues using an expert usability approach to design meaningful solutions to keep users in control during interactions. Develop strong relationships with developers, product managers, and users by tailoring a flexible style to meet success.

#### **Technical Skills**

User Research Survey / Interview, Empathy Map, Competitive Analysis, Literature Review, User Flow /

IA, Affinity Diagram, Persona / Journey Map, Usability Testing

**Design** Hand Sketches, Wireframes, Mockups, Prototypes, Design Systems

**Development** HTML5, CSS3, jQuery / JavaScript, Bootstrap

Tools Sketch, Figma, Adobe Suite (XD / Photoshop / Illustrator), Balsamiq, InVision, Frontify,

Zeplin, Visual Web Optimizer

# **Professional Experience**

#### QUEST SOFTWARE, Aliso Viejo, CA

2016 - 2020

#### Senior UX / UI Designer

2018 - 2020

- Preserved 15% of PMs' time on executing projects from planning to closure by designing project planning and reporting features for an internal product from conception to implementation, improving workflow for several departments.
- Initiated building a scalable responsive/accessible design library and defined maintenance process slashed design deliverables time 50% and enhanced design consistency across products.
- Achieved 10% in deflection by redefining and automating user-flow challenges to contact support in all devices.

UX / UI Designer 2016 - 2018

- Evaluated and redesigned Quest e-commerce to create visually stimulating UI and delightful user experience; collaborated with users, stakeholders, and developers. Yielded reduction in customer support costs by 20%.
- Led qualitative and quantitative research efforts such as A/B testing using visual web optimizer, validating designs and training team members improving conversion rate.

 Pioneered resolving problems by introducing new tools, facilitating hand-off procedures to developers, accelerating work efficiency.

## DELL SOFTWARE, Aliso Viejo, CA

2014 - 2016

#### **UI Developer**

- Launched pixel-perfect responsive web pages using Bootstrap framework amplified traffic and reduced bounce rate on tablet and mobile.
- Delivered a video gallery site using complex Ajax technology, enabling Dell to integrate overall video strategy across platforms improving accessibility.
- Partnered and trained remote employees around the world in an agile work environment, reducing project delays.

#### QUICKSTART INTELLIGENCE, Irvine, CA

2013 - 2014

#### **UI Developer**

- Developed interactive responsive components in collaboration with remote engineers boosting mobile traffic by 50%.
- Analyzed data and conducted qualitative usability tests with users, improving course registration rates by 0.2%
- Planned and executed code deployment process to production and conducted extensive user interface testing reducing bugs in live site

### **Side Projects**

FREELANCE 2020

#### **Product Designer**

- Designed a <u>COVID-19 protection concept mobile app</u> to help contain the Coronavirus through heatmaps, test symptoms, quarantine instructions, and assigning available healthcare facilities accordingly.
- Designed a healthcare mobile app to support virtual care, save commute time to a physical office, and access session recording on-demand; innovating a new concept in the healthcare industry.

## **Education**

- Master of Information Technology, Web Development, Swinburne University of Technology, Melbourne, Australia
- Bachelor of Computer Science, Hardware Engineering, Azad University, Tehran, Iran
- Certificate of Mobile User Experience (UX) Design, Interaction Design Foundation, Online
- Certificate of Emotional Design How to Make Products People Will Love, Interaction Design Foundation,
  Online
- Certificate of User Experience and Customer-Centered Design, California State University Fullerton, CA